hashnode.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy

Hashnode, operated by LinearBytes Inc., located at 8 The Green, Suite #4582, Dover, DE 19901 ("Hashnode," "we," or "our"), recognizes the importance of your personal privacy. Therefore, we have created this Privacy Policy so that you know how we use and disclose your information when you make it available to us. The Privacy Policy below discloses our practices regarding information collection and usage for the website located at hashnode.com and the related mobile website (collectively, the "Websites"), and the service provided thereon (the "Service").

By using or accessing the Websites and the Service, you signify your agreement to be bound by this Privacy Policy. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE OUR SERVICE OR PARTICIPATE IN OUR SERVICES.

Key aspects of our privacy practices described in this Privacy Policy include the following explanations:

  * The information we collect and why we collect it;
  * How we use that information;
  * How we share information; and
  * The choices we offer.

## Scope of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy only applies to your use of Our Site and does not extend to any websites that are referenced by to linked to from Our Site, whether by Us or another user. Your use of any other websites is subject to that website’s privacy policy and we have no control over how your data is collected, used, or stored by other websites. You are advised to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing data to them.

## Personally Identifiable Information That We Collect:

We may ask you for, or you may voluntarily submit, personally identifiable information when you are using the Service. The personally identifiable information which you may provide to us could include, but is not limited to:

  * Your name
  * Your contact information (including, without limitation, address and email address);
  * Your payment information; and
  * Any other personal information that is necessary to perform the actions requested by the user.

## Non-Personal Or Aggregate Information That We Collect:

When you access our Service, we may automatically collect non-personally identifiable information from you, such as IP host address, web pages viewed, browser type, operating system, referring service, search information, device type, page views, usage and browsing habits on the Service and similar data. We may also aggregate demographic information collected from our users (such as the number of users in a particular geographical location) in a manner which does not identify any one individual. We may also aggregate information collected offline in connection with the Service, obtain non-personally identifiable information from third party sources and develop aggregate information by anonymizing previously collected personally identifiable information.

It is possible at times when collecting non-personally identifiable information through automatic means that we may unintentionally collect or receive personally identifiable information that is mixed in with the non-personally identifiable information. While we will make reasonable efforts to prevent such incidental data collection, the possibility still exists. If you believe that we have inadvertently collected your personal information, please notify us at [hello@hashnode.com](mailto:hello@hashnode.com).

## Information Usage:

We will only use your personally identifiable information as described below, unless you have specifically consented to another type of use, either at the time the personally identifiable information is collected from you or through some other form of consent from you or notification to you:

  * We may share your personally identifiable information collected in connection with providing the Service, including sharing your data with other companies in Our group, including holding companies or subsidiaries.
  * We may use your personally identifiable information to respond to your inquires or requests.
  * With your permission or where permitted by law, We may use your personally identifiable information to send you emails from time to time about our services, but we will not provide your personally identifiable information to third parties for them to contact you directly unless otherwise permitted by this Privacy Policy or you provide your consent. We will not, however, send you any unsolicited marketing or spam and for users located in Europe, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that We fully protect your rights and comply with Our obligations under the GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, as amended in 2004, 2011 and 2015.
  * We may share your personally identifiable information with third parties (collectively, the "Third Party Vendors") to further the purpose for which you provided such information to us. For example, we may share your information our email platform, for the purpose of sending emails or with other vendors for the purposes of payment processing, delivery of goods, search engine facilities, advertising and marketing. In some cases, the third parties may require access to some or all of your data. Where any of your data is required for such a purpose, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data will be handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, Our obligations, and the obligations of the third party under the law. **We urge you to read the privacy practices of all of our Third Party Vendors before submitting any personally identifiable information through the Service.**
  * We may disclose personally identifiable information as required by law or legal process. For example, where We are involved in legal proceedings, where We are complying with the requirements of legislation, a court order, or a governmental authority. We do not require any further consent from you in order to share your data in such circumstances and will comply as required with any legally binding request that is made of Us.
  * We may disclose personally identifiable information to investigate suspected fraud, harassment or other violations of any law, rule or regulation, or the terms or policies for our services or our sponsors.
  * We may transfer your personally identifiable information in connection with the sale or merger or change of control of Hashnode or the division responsible for the services with which your personally identifiable information is associated. In the event of a sale, merger, or transfer, the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Privacy Policy, be permitted to use the data for the purposes for which it was originally collected by Us. In the event that any of your data is to be transferred in such a manner, you may not be contacted in advance or informed of the changes. 
  * We may share your personally identifiable information with an affiliate of Hashnode who is in the same corporate family as us as long as their privacy practices are substantially similar to ours.

## For European Citizens

All personal data is stored securely in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) (GDPR). For more details on security see section 6, below.

In some cases, the collection of data may be a statutory or contractual requirement, and We will be limited in the [products and] services We can provide you without your consent for Us to be able to use such data.

Under GDPR we will ensure that your personal data is processed lawfully, fairly, and transparently, without adversely affecting your rights. We will only process your personal data if at least one of the following basis applies:

  * you have given consent to the processing of your personal data for one or more specific purposes;
  * processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or in order to take steps at the request of you prior to entering into a contract;
  * processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject;
  * processing is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or of another natural person;
  * processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller; and/or
  * processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal data, in particular where the data subject is a child.

Non-personally identifiable or aggregate information may be used by us for any purposes permitted by law and may be shared with any number of parties, provided that such information shall not specifically identify you.

## Name and Profile Photo

By uploading your name and/or photograph to the Websites, you agree that this information will be posted publicly on the Websites.

## Cookies and Similar Technologies:

"Cookies" are pieces of information that may be placed on your computer by a service for the purpose of facilitating and enhancing your communication and interaction with that service. Many services use cookies for these purposes. We may use cookies (and similar items such as clear gifs, web beacons, tags, etc.) on our Service to customize your visit and for other purposes to make your visit more convenient or to enable us to enhance our Service. We may also use and place cookies (and similar items) on your computer from our third party service providers in connection with the Service, such as an analytics provider that helps us manage and analyze Service usage, as described more fully below. In addition, our advertisers and business partners may set cookies and similar items on your computer when you use our Service. You may stop or restrict the placement of cookies on your computer or flush them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences, in which case you may still use our Service, but it may interfere with some of its functionality. Cookies and similar items are not used by us to automatically retrieve personally identifiable information from your computer without your knowledge.

If you delete your cookies, change browsers or use a different cookie, our cookie (or an opt-out cookie) may no longer work and you will have to reinput (or opt-out) again.

## Analytics and Conversion Tracking:

We use analytics services that use cookies, JavaScript and similar technologies to help us analyze how users use the Service. The information generated by these services about your use of the Service (including your IP address or a truncated version of your IP address) is transmitted to and stored by analytics service providers on their servers. Those service providers will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your, and other users’, use of the Service, compiling reports for us on website activity and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage.

We may collect information about your computer, including your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and in order to create reports. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

We use cookies on our site for Google Analytics (the "Analytics Service"). The Analytics Service is a web analytics tool that helps website owners understand how visitors engage with their website. The Analytics Service customers can view a variety of reports about how visitors interact with their website so that they can improve it.

Like many services, the Analytics Service uses first-party cookies to track visitor interactions as in our case, where they are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We then use the information to compile reports and to help us improve our site.

Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive. These cookies are used to store information, such as the time that the current visit occurred, whether the visitor has been to the site before and what site referred the visitor to the web page.

The Analytics Service collects information anonymously. It reports website trends without identifying individual visitors. You can opt out of the Analytics Service without affecting how you visit our site. For more information on opting out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites you use, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

We also use Google conversion tracking and/or similar services to help us understand your and other users’ use of the Service.

Please see <https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/1722022?hl=en> for more information about conversion tracking provided by Google.

## Automatically Collected Information:

When you access the Service or open one of our HTML emails, we may automatically record certain information from your system by using cookies and other types of tracking technologies. This "automatically collected" information may include Internet Protocol address ("IP Address"), a unique user ID, device type, device identifiers, browser types and language, referring and exit pages, platform type, version of software installed, system type, the content and pages that you access on the Service, the number of clicks, the amount of time spent on pages, the dates and times that you visit the Service, and other similar information. Depending on the law of your country of residence, your IP address may legally be considered personally identifiable information.

## Security:

The security of your personally identifiable information is very important to us. When we collect your personally identifiable information online, we use reasonable efforts to protect it from unauthorized access. However, due to the inherent open nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that your personally identifiable information will be completely free from unauthorized access by third parties such as hackers and your use of our Service demonstrates your assumption of this risk. We have put in place reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect. Only those employees who need access to your information in order to perform their duties are authorized to have access to your personally identifiable information. For more information on protecting your privacy, please visit www.ftc.gov/privacy.

We only keep your data for as long as We need to in order to use it as described above in section 5, or for as long as We have your permission to keep it. In any event, We will conduct an annual review to ascertain whether we need to keep your data. Your data will be deleted if we no longer need it in accordance with the terms of our Data Retention Policy.

Some or all of your data may be stored or transferred outside of the European Economic Area (“the EEA”) (The EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein). You are deemed to accept and agree to this by using Our Site and submitting information to Us. If We do store or transfer data outside the EEA, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the EEA and under the GDPR. Such steps may include, but not be limited to, the use of legally binding contractual terms between Us and any third parties We engage and the use of the EU-approved Model Contractual Arrangements. 

Data security is of great importance to Us, and to protect your data We have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure data collected through Our Site.

Specific steps we take to secure and protect your data include, but are not limited to: 

  1. Encrypting the connection between our website and your computer 
  2. Ensuring the physical and digital security of the servers holding your data
  3. Controlling the access Our staff and contractors have to the data to ensure that only authorised personnel are able to access the data.

Notwithstanding the security measures that We take, it is important to remember that the transmission of data via the internet may not be completely secure and that you are advised to take suitable precautions when transmitting to Us data via the internet.

## How You Can Control Your Data

When you submit information via Our Site, you may be given options to restrict Our use of your data. We aim to give you control on Our use of your data (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from Us which you may do by unsubscribing using the links provided in Our emails).

## Accessing Your Data

You have the legal right to ask for a copy of any of your personal data held by Us (where such data is held). Please contact Us for more details at using the information in the Contact section below.

## Right to Withhold Information and Your Right to Withdraw Information After You Have Given It

For European users subject to GDPR, you may access certain areas of Our Site without providing any data at all. However, to use all features and functions available on Our Site you may be required to submit or allow for the collection of certain data.

You may restrict your internet browser’s use of Cookies and clear Cookies from your browser at any time.

You may withdraw your consent for Us to use your personal data as set out in this privacy policy at any time by contacting Us using the information in the Contact section below, and We will delete Your data from Our systems. However, you acknowledge that this may limit our ability to provide the best possible product and services to you.

## Your Disclosures In Blogs And Other Social Media:

You should be aware that personally identifiable information which you voluntarily include and transmit online on the Service or in a publicly accessible blog, chat room, social media platform or otherwise online, or that you share in an open forum such as an in-person panel or survey, may be viewed and used by others without any restrictions. We are unable to control such uses of your personally identifiable information, and by using the Service or any other online services you assume the risk that the personally identifiable information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties for any number of purposes.

If you login to the Websites and/or Service through your Facebook account, connect to a third party service such as Facebook or Twitter through an icon or link on the Service or otherwise link your Hashnode account with a third party service, we may share the contents of your post and associated information (such as your user name, the fact that your connection originated from the Service, and other relevant usage and diagnostic information) with such third party. With your one-time consent, we may also send information about the content you watch and your activities on the Service to such third parties. Once such information is shared, the use of your information will be subject to that service's privacy policy and this Privacy Policy will not apply.

## Protection for Children:

We generally do not collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If at any time in the future we plan to collect personally identifiable information from children under 13, such collection and use, to the extent applicable, shall, when required, be done in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA") and appropriate consent from the child’s parent or guardian will be sought where required by COPPA. When we become aware that personally identifiable information from a child under 13 has been collected without such child’s parent or guardian’s consent, we will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

## Other Services:

As a convenience to you, we may provide links to third-party Services from within our Service. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these third-party sites. When you link away from our Service, you do so at your own risk.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy:

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this Privacy Policy at any time. However, if at any time in the future we plan to use personally identifiable information in a way that materially differs from this Privacy Policy, including sharing such information with more third parties, we will post such changes here and provide you the opportunity to opt-out of such differing uses. Your continued use of the Service and our services following the posting of any changes to this Privacy Policy means you accept such changes.

## Opt-Out Process:

All unsubscribe or opt-out requests may be made by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the email or by changing the email preferences in your account settings. We will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. However, we are not responsible for, and in some cases we are incapable of, removing your personally identifiable information from the lists of any third party who has previously been provided your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy or your consent. You should contact such third parties directly. If you would like to update or correct any personally identifiable information that you have provided to us, please email us at Hashnode and once we confirm your information, we will update such information within a reasonable amount of time.

## Communications with Hashnode:

By providing your email address, phone number, and/or social media information (collectively the "Channels") to us, you expressly consent to receive communications from us. We may use the Channels to communicate with you, to send information that you have requested or to send information about other products or services developed or provided by us or our business partners, provided that, we will not give your contact information to another party to promote their products or services directly to you without your consent or as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

By providing your phone number to us, you expressly consent to receive phone calls and/or text messages from us. We will not give your phone number to another party to promote their products or services directly to you without your consent or as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Any phone calls and/or text messages delivered to your phone or device may cause you to incur extra data, text messaging, or other charges from your wireless carrier. MESSAGE AND DATA RATES MAY APPLY. You are solely responsible for any carrier charges incurred as a result of phone and/or text communications from Hashnode.

Any communication or material you transmit to us by email or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions, or the like is, and will be treated as, non-confidential and nonproprietary. Except to the extent expressly covered by this Privacy Policy, anything you transmit or post may be used by us for any purpose, including but not limited to, reproduction, disclosure, transmission, publication, broadcast and posting. Furthermore, you expressly agree that we are free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how, or techniques contained in any communication you send to us, as well as any data developed using the content of such communication, without compensation and for any purpose whatsoever, including but not limited to, developing, manufacturing and marketing products and services using such information.

## No Rights of Third Parties:

This Privacy Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties, nor does it require disclosure of any personal information relating to users of the Service.

## Site Terms of Use:

Use of this Service is governed by, and subject to, the Terms of Use located at [the "Terms"](https://hashnode.com/terms). This Privacy Policy is incorporated into the Terms. Your use, or access, of the Service constitutes your agreement to be bound by these provisions. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS AND THIS PRIVACY POLICY YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE SERVICE.

## Servers:

Our servers are maintained in the United States. By using the Service, you freely and specifically give us your consent to export your personally identifiable information to the United States and to store and use it in the United States as specified in this Privacy Policy. You understand that data stored in the United States may be subject to lawful requests by the courts or law enforcement authorities in the United States.

## European Citizens – Your Rights Under GDPR:

Under the GDPR, you have:

  * the right to request access to, deletion of or correction of, your personal data held by Us; 
  * the right to complain to a supervisory authority;
  * be informed of what data processing is taking place;
  * the right to restrict processing;
  * the right to data portability;
  * object to processing of your personal data;
  * rights with respect to automated decision-making and profiling.

To enforce any of the foregoing rights or if you have any other questions about Our Site or this Privacy Policy, please contact Us using the details set out in the Contact section below.

## Governing Law:

This Privacy Policy and our legal obligations hereunder are subject to the laws of Delaware regardless of your location. You hereby consent to the exclusive jurisdiction of and venue in the courts located in Sussex County, Delaware, in all disputes arising out of or relating to the Services.

## Contact:

For questions or concerns relating to privacy, we can be contacted at [hello@hashnode.com](mailto:hello@hashnode.com).

Our data protection officer is Sandeep Panda who can be contacted at [sandeep@hashnode.com](mailto:sandeep@hashnode.com).

>  **Effective from:**  
>  May 22, 2018 
> 
> **Updated on:**  
>  May 22, 2018
